Home Address: 62a Northside Wandsworth Common, SW18 2SH.
Mob: 07877 349981. Email: chrismhs@gmail.com
Portfolio: chris.hastings-spital.co.uk

Christopher Hastings-Spital (BA)

Personal Information

Date of Birth: May 29th 1987

Nationality: British

Profile

Chris is a confident, well-spoken and highly creative user experience and interaction Designer. His experience has nurtured a logical approach, an imaginative nature and a drive to push the boundaries of what's possible. Chris's agency background has provided excellent leadership qualities and an ability to complete projects within a strict deadline.

Chris is passionate about making websites and applications thats are optimised for performance as well as visually stunning. By working closely with developers on many large scale projects, he understands the limitations of what can be done with CSS, HTML and Javascript and therefore has the ability to push deliverables past what's expected.

In the part 5 years, Chris has worked in many lead designer roles in the UK and is looking to expand his knowledge by joining a team on an international stage.

Work History

BAE Systems Detica

July 2011 - Present

Senior user experience and interaction design consultant for the UK's no. 1 design and build digital agency (TheDrum - 2012).

- Lead designer for the new Transport for London device agnostic responsive website (due for launch spring 2013).
- UX and visual designer for Vodafone Freebees microsite.
- Lead designer for the London 2012 Olympic Games official travel website -GetAheadoftheGames.com.
- UX designer for a Leisure routes campaign for Barclay's London Cycle Hire.
- Designer for the VodafoneUK mobile framework.
- UX and Lead designer for the Orange App Finder.

BAM Agency

August 2009 - July 2011

Lead Designer for the largest Student Marketing Agency in the UK. The role included keeping to tight deadlines on internal and external projects.

Project include:

- NBC Universal 'Kick-Ass' Superhero Theme Student Events
- Download Festival Promotional Website
- Kit-Kat Battle of the Bands

Intosport.com - Online World Class Sports Coaching

May 2008 - June 2009

Heavy involvement in the creation of 40+ episodes of the 'David Lloyd Tennis Academy', including cameraman and head of animation/graphics. Tasks included editing in Final Cut Pro, building 3D animated models in Adobe After Effects and creating graphics for the entire series.

Additional roles include:

- Chief editor for the IntosportMedia episode and various other Intosport.com advertising films.
- Data aggregation for tens of thousands of sports centres for database development.

Freelance Designer and Filmographer

May 2005 - Present

Logo design for '4StudentHomes', University of Nottingham Capoeira Society, a start-up web company 'Spitweb', 'Lost.eu' Online Worldwide Game.

Articles for 'Alliance Wakeboard Magazine', 'Loughborough WOW' and 'Label' magazines

Education

Loughborough University

Sept 2005 - July 2008

Batchelor of Arts degree (BA) - Industrial Design & Manufacture

Key Course Modules: Entrepreneurship & Innovation, Advanced Photoshop Use, Design Practice, Illustrator Use, Prototype Manufacturing, Engineering Manufacture, Computer Aided Design, Web Design in Flash

Radley College, Oxfordshire

Sept 2000 - July 2005

A-levels in Design & Technology, Art, Physics and Mathematics.

Other Experience

UK National Cable Wakeboarding Judge

March 2009 - Present

Gained Highest National Level of Wakeboard Judging. Chief Judge of Student Nationals 2009, Judge for the UK Nationals 2009 and Judge for the Milton Keynes Summer Jam 2009.

Media Secretary of Loughborough University Wakeboard Club

2006-2008

Responsible for advertising and promotion of the club. Included logo design, video production, Photography and creating the LSUwake.com website.

CTi Knee-brace Representative

2007 - 2009

Promoting the UK's foremost knee-braces. Tasks included sponsored athlete action photography, creating promotional films and representative for the Wakeboard World Championships – (Camsur, Philippines 2009)